A Guide to the Alfred Ezra Mirsky papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA131
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Correspondence, 1929 1942-1974; 2
  - D-Des (Box 6)
    - Dalgliesh, C.E., 2 letters
    - Dall'Asta, E.R., 1 letter
    - Daly, Marie. Recommendations for D'Amelio, Vincenzo (7), 1955-1962; 14 letters
    - Dameri, Maria, 2 letters
    - Damon Runyon Memorial Fund for Cancer Research, 1 letter
    - Dana, Richard, 1 letter
    - Dane, Ralph, 2 letters
    - Danielli, J.F. Bristol Cytochemistry meeting and symposium; 2 mss reviews, 1951 July 5-13; 21 letters
    - Darnell, James, 6 letters
    - Das, C.C., 12 letters
    - Das, N.K., 3 letters
    - Dasgupta, J., 2 letters
    - Datta, R.K., 2 letters
    - Davidson, J.N. 1 item job inquiry for Peter Curtis, 18 letters
    - Davies, H.G., 5 letters
    - Dekker, Marcel. de Kloet, S.R. (9), 2 letters
    - Delacorte, George T., 2 letters
    - Delafresnaye, J.F. Marco Crippa recommendation, 4 letters
    - Delluva, Adelaide M. Eileen Sutton Gersh recommendation, 2 letters
    - Demerec, Milislav, 10 letters
      Includes 1 holograph; outline with notes on thoughts of writing Genetics 1960 book dedicated to Demerec.
    - Denev, Carl, 1 letter
    - Dennison, D.S., 2 letters
    - De Robertis, E., 2 letters
    - Desai, L., 1 letter
  - Deu-Dwy (Box 7)
    - Deutsche Akademie der Naturforscher Die Leopoldina, 7 letters
    - Deyrup, I., 3 letters
    - Diacumokos, Elaine. 2 research proposal evaluations, 26 letters
    - Dietz, Wm., 1 letter
    - Dixon, K.C. Paul Wilson recommendation, 3 letters
    - Dobzhansky, Theodosius, 8 letters
    - Dodge, Fred. Student progress report, 2 letters
    - Dole, Vincent P., 2 letters
    - Doty, Paul, 9 letters
      Includes 3 Doty reprints.
    - Doubleday, 8 letters
    - Doudney, CO, 1 letter
    - Dounce, A.L., 1942-1973; 8 letters
    - Drewnowski, Adam. Admission application, 6 letters
      Also see Brink.
    - Droz, Bernard, 2 letters
    - Dube, Shyam, 3 letters
    - Dubinin, N.P., 1 letter
    - Dubos, René. Ethical Culture Society Felix Adler lecture, 1970 May 21; 2 letters
      [See also under: Avery, Oswald Theodore in Box no. 29] Ducommun, M. Co. (1).
    - Dunn, L.C. Editor: American Naturalist, 6 letters
    - Durairaj, G., 2 letters
    - Dwyer, M.J., 3 letters
  - E-Ex (Box 7)
    - Earley, Edward F. "L'Etre Vivant" review, 3 letters
    - Early, Ruth, 2 letters
    - Eastern Psychiatric Research Assoc. address, 1959 October 24; 2 letters
    - Eastman Kodak Co., 1 letter
    - Ebai, T.A., 2 letters
    - Eberhart, Bruce, 7 letters
    - Ebert, James D., 3 letters
    - Eccles, John C., 1 letter
    - Eddy, Louise K., 1 letter
    - Edelman, Gerald M. Lorna Green student examination, 1 letter
    - Edelstein, Ludwig, 1960; 40 letters
      Includes many holograph letters; 32 items 1960 Aristotle Biology Seminars May 9, 11, 12, 16, 18, 19 with signed acceptances.
    - Edsall, J., 6 letters
    - Edwards, Diana, 1 letter
    - Egami, F., 3 letters
    - Ehrich, W., 1 letter
    - Ehrman, Lee, 1 letter
    - Eisenberg, R.I., 3 letters
    - Eli-Ani, Arif, 1 letter
    - Eliceiri, George L., 2 letters
    - Elliot, R.C., 16 letters
    - Elliott, Donald A., 2 letters
    - Elliott, K.A.C., 1 letter
    - Ellison, Rebecca, 2 letters
    - Elsevier Publishing Co., 7 letters
    - Encyclopaedia Britannica, 6 letters
    - Encyclopedia Americana, 3 letters
    - Endeavor, 1 letter
    - Engel, Leonard. suggested Breakthrough statement, 1962 November; 1 letter
    - Engelhardt, D.L., 1 letter
    - Engelhardt, W.A., 13 letters
    - Engelmann, Siegfried, 2 letters
    - Ephrussi, Boris, 2 letters
    - Erganian, Joseph, 4 letters
    - Erlandson, R.A., 2 letters
    - Erlenmeyer-Kimling, L., 1 letter
    - Errera, Maurice, 5 letters
    - Ethical Culture Society. addresses, 1970 May 1972 March 19; 17 letters
    - Ettinghausen, Richard. Recommendation for V. Clain-Stefanelli, numismatist, 2 letters
    - Evans, John H., 2 letters
    - Experimental Cell Research, 6 letters
      Includes L.A. Miller and A. Goldfelder ms review.
  - F-Foy (Box 7)
    - Fabian, Barry, 2 letters
    - Farber, Saul, 5 letters
    - Fautrez, J., 1 letter
    - Favelukes, G., 1 letter
    - Fawcett, Don W., 2 letters
    - Feldherr, Carl M., 3 letters
    - Fell, H.B., 2 letters
    - Feller, Will. Wyatt Anderson student examination, 5 letters
    - Feng, Te-pei, 1 letter
    - Fenn, Wallace O., 1 letter
    - Fernandez-Moran, H., 2 letters
    - Fiala, Silvio, 2 letters
    - Filipowicz, B. Concerning Henryk Panusz, 3 letters
    - Finch, Caleb, 5 letters
    - Finney, R.J., 1 letter
    - Fischberg, M. Concerning Marco Crippa, 2 letters
    - Fitton-Jackson, Sylvia. Concerning The Cell, 12 letters
    - Fleming, Donald, 1 letter
    - Flinn, Waldo R., 17 letters
    - Flory, P.J. (1)
    - Foley, Tom, 25 letters
      Includes items on admission application.
    - Follansbee, S.E., 2 letters
    - Ford Foundation, 1950-1972; 12 letters
      Includes grant proposal evaluations: Sir Andrew B. Cohen; Etienne Baulieu.
    - Forest, Herman S., 2 letters
    - Forman, Arthur. Recommendations for Forsdyke, D. (2), 32 letters
    - Forster, Roy P. Werner Maas recommendation, 2 letters
    - Foster, John. Columbia University seminar, Advanced Science Writing Program Fox, H. Munro (2), 1958 December 18; 1 letter
    - Fox, Sidney W. Irving Goodman recommendation, 15 letters
    - Foxworth, S., 1 letter
    - Foyn, B. Hans Saetren recommendation, 2 letters
  - Fran-Fur (Box 7)
    - Francis, Thomas. Syozo Osawa recommendation, 6 letters
    - Frankfurt, Harry, 4 letters
    - Fraser, D.K., 1 letter
    - Fraser, I.E.B., 3 letters
    - Fraser, Ian M., 2 letters
    - Frederick, J.E., 1 letter
    - Fremont-Smith, Frank. 1 holograph, 2 letters
    - Frenster, John H., 1957-1971; 55 letters
    - Fricke, Hugo, 2 letters
    - Friedman, B., 2 letters
    - Friedman, H., 2 letters
    - Friedrich-Freska, H. Tübingen, Miescher symposium, 1969 September; 2 letters
    - Frings, Hubert, 1 letter
    - Fristrom, James W., 1 letter
    - Fritz, K. von, 1 letter
    - Frhølm, L.O., 5 letters
    - Fruton, Joseph S., 6 letters
    - Fryer, J.R., 2 letters
    - Fulton, Chandler. Student progress report, 2 letters
    - Furth, Jacob. Comments on Stasney et al ms, 2 letters
  - G-Gel (Box 7)
    - Gaffey, C.T., 2 letters
    - Gais, Ruth M., 2 letters
    - Gabrieli, E.R., 2 letters
    - Gall, Joseph, 1 letter
    - Gallard-Schlesinger Chemical Mfg. Corp., 1 letter
    - Gallego, Antonio. Items on 1963 Aug 5-12 Santander, Spain International Meeting lecture; job inquiry for J. Tamarit Jr., 1963 August 5-12; 12 letters
    - Gallwitz, Dieter, 2 letters
    - Gambino, Ann, 2 letters
    - Gardella, Catherine, 2 letters
    - Gardner, Frank T., 2 letters
    - Gasic, Gabriel, 1957-1974; 38 letters
      Includes 1960 Santiago, Chile lectures; recommendation for.
    - Gasser, Herbert S., 8 letters
    - Gehuchten, P. Van. Concerning J. Fautrez work, 2 letters
    - Geiger, Alexander and Ruth, 9 letters
    - Gelles, J., 20 letters
    - Gelles, M. Comments on ms "The Work of the Actuary", 2 letters
  - Gen-Ger (Box 7)
    - Genetics, 4 letters
    - Genetics Society of America. 1944 holograph; primarily 1952, 89 letters
    - German, James, 3 letters
  - Gerr-Gran (Box 8)
    - Gerring, Irving, 2 letters
    - Gersh, Eileen S., 4 letters
    - Gersh, Isidore, 1949-1974; 6 letters
    - Gershon, David, 2 letters
    - Gertiser, R., 2 letters
    - Ghiretti, Francesco, 1 letter
    - Ghosh, A.N., 1 letter
    - Gibor, Aharon. Recommendation for, 2 letters
    - Giese, Arthur C. Nucleus chapter review in "Cell Physiology", 46 letters
      Includes chapter "Chemical Organization and Function of the Cell Nucleus".
    - Gilding, H.P., 3 letters
    - Gilford Instrument Labs, 2 letters
    - Ginsberg, H.S., 1 letter
    - Giovanella, B.C., 2 letters
    - Glass, H. Bentley, 2 letters
    - Glick, David, 5 letters
    - Goddard, David R.; R.W. Merriam evaluation, 1948-1966; 9 letters
    - Goethe, John W., 2 letters
    - Gold, Albert, 7 letters
    - Goldberg, Irving. Student progress report, 2 letters
    - Goldman, James A., 2 letters
    - Gonze, J., 2 letters
    - Good, Thomas A., 2 letters
    - Goodman, Walter. Redbook DNA article evaluation, 3 letters
    - Gordon, R.E., 2 letters
    - Gordon, S., 1 letter
    - Gott, Peggy, 1 letter
    - Grand Island Biological Co., 6 letters
    - Granick, Sam, 2 letters
    - Grant, Diane, 2 letters
  - Gras-Gust (Box 8)
    - Grassman, W. Heinz Tiedemann recommendation, 5 letters
    - Gray, George W. Review of "Nucleoproteins" article, 11 letters
    - Griffiths, Raymond B. John Frenster ms comments, 2 letters
    - Grimshaw, William H., 2 letters
    - Gross, Paul. Recommendation to C.F. Barlow, 3 letters
    - Gruber, M. Items concerning R.N. Campagne, 11 letters
    - Grun, Paul, 2 letters
    - Gryczan, Thomas, 2 letters
    - Guerdat, D., 2 letters
    - Guggenheim Memorial Foundation. Grant evaluations; fellowship recommendation for Niu, 11 letters
    - Gupta, K.C., 2 letters
    - Gurdon, John, 7 letters
    - Gustafson, Tryggve, 3 letters
  - H-Herc (Box 8)
    - Habibulla, M., 2 letters
    - Haemmerling, J., 2 letters
    - Haidemankis, E.D., 2 letters
    - Hakim, Anwar, 3 letters
    - Haldane, J.B.S., 10 letters
    - Hall, B.D., 1 letter
    - Hall, E.T., 1 letter
    - Hallier, Ulrich, 2 letters
    - Hamburger, Viktor. St. Louis, Mo. Washington University Journal Club address, 1951 November 8; 8 letters
    - Hamilton, Terrel. Recommendation to Schrank, 2 letters
    - Handler, Philip, 3 letters
    - Hansch, Corwin H., 3 letters
    - Hanson, Earl D., 2 letters
    - Harding, Clifford V., 1952-1965; 30 letters
      Includes correspondence concerning A.E. Mirsky preface to "The Nuclear Membrane and Nucleocytoplasmic Interchange" (see mss box 35).
    - Harris, Beulah, 2 letters
    - Harris, Frank, 1 letter
    - Harris, R.J., 1 letter
    - Harrison, Marion F., 1 letter
    - Hartog, Annemarie, 2 letters
    - Hartree, E.F., 3 letters
    - Harvard University Press. Special review on Jacques Loeb "The Mechanistic Concept of Life", 7 letters
    - Hashimoto, Chieko, 1 letter
    - Hastings, J. Woodland, 1 letter
    - Hay, Elizabeth, 1 letter
    - Hayashi, Yujiro, 2 letters
    - Heber, Rick F., 2 letters
    - Heidelberger, Michael. On P.A.T. Leven chemicals, 3 letters
    - Heilweil, I.J., 1 letter
    - Heller, I.H., 2 letters
    - Hellerstein, David. Fieldston School student, 2 letters
    - Henderson, Harry (A) DNA ms review for Image
    - Henel, R.H., 3 letters
    - Henley, F. Austin, 2 letters
    - Hercik, Ferdinand, 1949-1964; 12 letters
      Includes job inquiry for M. Skalka.
  - Herm-Hur (Box 8)
    - Herman, M. Jean, 1 letter
    - Hermann, Heinz, 4 letters
    - Hershey, A.D., 5 letters
    - Hess, Adolph, 2 letters
    - Hess, Robert, 1 letter
    - Hevesy, G. de, 2 letters
    - Hidvegi, E.J., 1 letter
    - Hirsch, Jerry, 4 letters
      Includes listing of Cattell material.
    - Hirsch, Jules, 1 letter
    - Hoagland, Mahlon B., 3 letters
    - Hoberman, Henry D., 3 letters
    - Hoecker, Gustavo, 5 letters
    - Hoffstedt, Maud, 2 letters
    - Hokin, Lowell E., 5 letters
    - Holden-Day, 3 letters
    - Holley, L., 2 letters
    - Holley, Robert, 1 letter
    - Holman, Halsted R. John Frenster recommendation, 3 letters
    - Holschuh, Karl, 2 letters
    - Hopkins, Johns III. Recommendations; thesis evaluation, 11 letters
    - Hornig, Joanna G. Admission application, 4 letters
    - Horwitz, Alan F., 2 letters
    - Hossainy, Effat, 2 letters
    - Hough, Barbara, 1 letter
    - Houghton Mifflin Co., 12 letters
    - Howell, Clark, 2 letters
    - Hsu, T'C, 1 letter
    - Hubel, David H., 1 letter
    - Hughes, Roscoe D., 3 letters
    - Hurley, Kenneth E., 6 letters
      Includes W.S. Stone recommendation.
    - Hurvitz, Arthur I., 1 letter
  - Hydén, Holger, 1950-1974; 115 letters (Box 8)
    Includes 5 mss.
  - I-Ju (Box 8)
    - Impey, Oliver, 1 letter
    - Inander, A.R., 2 letters
    - Indian Scientists and Students. Miscellaneous correspondence, 2 letters
    - Ingle, Dwight, 1 letter
    - Ingram, Rupert H., 2 letters
    - Institute of Cancer Research, 1 letter
    - International Society for Cell Biology, 11 letters
    - Interscience Publishers, 4 letters
    - Irwin, Marion, 1 letter
    - Irwin, M.R., 7 letters
      Includes 1 holograph; Hans Ris nomination for election to NAS.
    - Israelstam, Gerald F., 1 letter
    - Italian Encyclopedia, 2 letters
    - Itzhaki, Ruth F., 16 letters
    - Iyengar, M. Raja, 2 letters
    - Izawa, Mitsuo. 6 holographs, 31 letters
    - Jacobsen, Ed, 2 letters
    - Jacobson, Terry, 2 letters
    - Jaffe, Herbert, 1 letter
    - Jaffe, Lionel, 2 letters
    - Jan, M.K.Y., 2 letters
    - Jeljaszewicz, J., 2 letters
    - Jenkins, Donald P., 2 letters
    - Jensen, Arthur R., 4 letters
    - Johnson, Jerry D., 2 letters
    - Jones, Betty, 2 letters
    - Jones, Larry H., 1 letter
    - Journal of Clinical Investigation. Leuchtenberger ms review, 3 letters
    - Journal of General Physiology, 15 letters
      Includes 1961 letter of resignation as Editor and responses.
    - Journal of Physical Chemistry, 1 letter
    - Journal of Theoretical Biology, 3 letters
    - Joyce-Loebl Co., 1 letter
    - Judkins, Esther. Concerning library, 2 letters
    - Jukes, Tan. Concerning A.E. Mirsky N Y Times Letter to Editor, 1971 August 8; 1 letter
  - K-Kle (Box 9)
    - Kac, Mark. On Michael Cole appointment, 2 letters
    - Kahn, K., 2 letters
    - Kalnins, V., 1 letter
    - Kaltenbach, John P., 1 letter
    - Kalyanasundaram, R., 4 letters
    - Kanazir, Dusan. Visiting Yugoslavian scientist, 2 letters
    - Kandasamy, V., 4 letters
    - Kansas State. D.W. Janes job inquiry, 2 letters
    - Kanungo, M.S., 1964-1973; 24 letters
      Includes Moudgil thesis review.
    - Kappas, Attallah, 1 letter
    - Karanfilska, Natalija, 1 letter
    - Karlson, Peter, 2 letters
    - Karnofsky, David A., 1 letter
    - Kashket, S., 7 letters
    - Katana-Mbabi, Solomon, 1 letter
    - Katz, Bernard, 6 letters
    - Katz, Sherman, 2 letters
    - Kaufmann, B.P., 2 letters
    - Kavenoff, Ruth, 1 letter
    - Kay, Ernest R.M., 19 letters
    - Keesee, T.W., 1 letter
    - Keiles, Elsa O., 1 letter
    - Kellner, Aaron. A.O. Pogo recommendation, 2 letters
    - Kellog, A. Remington. Concerning Clain-Stefanelli, numismatist, 2 letters
    - Kelly, Jerome, 2 letters
    - Kerzin, B., 1 letter
    - Kessler, Alex, 1 letter
    - Kety, Seymour, 3 letters
    - Khuri, Nicola N., 1 letter
    - Kidd, John, 1 letter
    - Kidd, Kenneth K., 2 letters
    - Kilbourne, Edwin. Eduardo Scarano recommendation, 3 letters
    - Kimball, R.F., 1 letter
    - Kimmel, Donald L., 1 letter
    - Kimura, Doreen, 2 letters
    - Kistiakowsky, G.B. NAS committee on government relations, 8 letters
    - Kischer, C. Ward, 2 letters
    - Kleczkowska, Danuta, 2 letters
    - Klein, Dennis, 1 letter
    - Klein, Harold P., 2 letters
    - Kleinsmith, Lewis, 1 letter
    - Klejman, J.J., 1 letter
  - Kli-Ky (Box 9)
    - Kline, Robert, 1 letter
    - Kling, Vincent G., 2 letters
    - Klose, Joachim, 2 letters
    - Klouwen, Herman M., 8 letters
    - Knight, Donald. Student application, 9 letters
    - Knopf, Alfred A., 2 letters
    - Kochakian, Charles D. 1963 Dec 2 University Alabama lecture, 1963 December 2; 11 letters
    - Koerner, James F., 4 letters
    - Kohn, Henry I., 4 letters
    - Kohne, David E., 2 letters
    - Koller, P.C., 1 letter
    - Kone, Eugene H., 1 letter
    - Koningsberger, V.V. Concerning S.R. de Kloet, 12 letters
    - Koshland, D.E. Jr., 2 letters
    - Koster, Lewis J., 1 letter
    - Koyal, Dipali, 2 letters
    - Krebs, Hans A., 6 letters
    - Krieghbaum, Hillier, 4 letters
    - Krishna, Murthy A.S., 2 letters
    - Krishnasawamy, S., 2 letters
    - Kritzler, Henry. Concerning Holger Hyden, 4 letters
    - Krivoy, W., 1 letter
    - Kroeger, H., 6 letters
    - Krupp, Marcus A., 1 letter
    - Kuehl, LeRoy, 4 letters
    - Kugelmass, I.N., 2 letters
    - Kumar, K. Anand, 2 letters
    - Kurnick, N.B., 1 letter
    - Kurtz, Paul, 2 letters
    - Kyle, Roy E., 1 letter
  - L-Lip (Box 9)
    - Ladd Research Industries, 1 letter
    - Lafer, D.J., 3 letters
    - Lafontaine, J.G., 5 letters
    - Lamla, E., 1 letter
    - Landauer, W., 1 letter
    - Landry, Stuart O., 3 letters
    - Lang, Anton, 2 letters
    - Larrabee, Martin G., 4 letters
    - Laskowski, M., 5 letters
    - Lauffer, Max, 1 letter
    - Laughlin, William S., 2 letters
    - Leblond, CP, 1 letter
    - Lederberg, Joshua, 4 letters
      Includes ms review for Science [See also under: Avery, Oswald Theodore in Box no. 29].
      See also: Avery, Oswald Theodore in Box 29.
    - Le Donne, John P., 2 letters
    - Lee, Pamela, 2 letters
    - Lee Mr, 2 letters
    - Lemon, Henry M., 2 letters
    - Leppard, Gary, 1 letter
    - Lerner, I. Michael. Concerning objection to holding XI International Congress of Genetics in Germany, 3 letters
    - Lestina, Letitia, 4 letters
    - Lettré, Renate, 1 letter
    - Levine, Howard, 3 letters
    - Levi-Montalcini, Rita, 1 letter
    - Levine, Phil, 1 letter
    - Levine, R.P., 2 letters
    - Lewis, Cynthia, 2 letters
    - Lewis, George, 2 letters
    - Lewis, Gladys, 1 letter
    - Lewis, Robert B., 3 letters
    - Lezzi, Markus, 2 letters
    - Lhofova, Jane, 2 letters
    - Li, Hsueh-jei, 1 letter
    - Library of Congress, 2 letters
    - Lichtenstein, Cecile, 1 letter
    - Liljestrand, G., 2 letters
    - Lin, Mei, 25 letters
    - Lin, Michael, 2 letters
    - Linderstrøm-Lang, Kai, 2 letters
    - Lindheim, Roslyn, 1 letter
    - Lindsay, David t. Ms review, 2 letters
    - Lipmann, Fritz, 4 letters
    - Lipschutz, Alejandro, 4 letters
    - Lipsitt, Lewis P., 8 letters
  - Lit-Ly (Box 9)
    - Littau, Virginia, 11 letters
    - Livingston, Luzern G., 3 letters
    - LoBue, Bonnie, 1 letter
    - Loewenberg, Jakob R., 2 letters
    - Loewenstein, Werner R., 1 letter
    - London, Irving M., 3 letters
    - Long, M.E., 2 letters
    - Lonnqvist, Jan-Olov, 1 letter
    - Looney, William B., 1959-1966; 19 letters
    - Love, Bruce B., 4 letters
    - Low, Frank N., 2 letters
    - Lowe, Charles U., 1 letter
    - Lowry, Oliver H., 1 letter
    - Lubimova, M.N., 1 letter
    - Lucas, Jim, 1 letter
    - Luck, J. Murray, 7 letters
    - Luft, Rolf, 2 letters
    - Lundin, Harry, 1 letter
    - Lupinek, Bernard, 4 letters
    - Luria, S.E. 1 holograph, 8 letters
      Includes items on draft NAS statement on Vietnam War.
    - Lyons, David J., 2 letters
  - M-Maz (Box 9)
    - Maas, Werner K., 2 letters
    - Mach, Bernard. Thesis evaluation, 2 letters
    - Mac Innes, Duncan A. APS grant application evaluations, 9 letters
    - Mackenzie, Julia, 6 letters
      Includes work evaluation to T.T. Puck.
    - Mac Lane, Saunders, 1 letter
    - Maclean, Norman, 16 letters
    - Macleod, A. Garrard, 2 letters
    - Madison, Leonard L. University Texas seminar, 1966 November 30; 2 letters
    - Maheshwari, Satish C., 4 letters
    - Maimonides Hospital, 5 letters
    - Malkin, Leonard I., 2 letters
    - Mandel, Morton, 2 letters
    - Mangan, Jerrome, 3 letters
    - Maramorosch, Karl. Recommendation for Lalor Research Award, 3 letters
    - Mark, H., 1 letter
    - Markert, Clement L., 7 letters
      Includes letters in defense.
    - Marler, Peter, 5 letters
    - Marr, Eleanor B., 2 letters
    - Marshak, R.E., 1 letter
    - Marshall, John M., 3 letters
    - Martin, May, 1 letter
    - Mastrangelo, Iris A., 2 letters
    - Matoltsy, A.G., 1 letter
    - Mauritzen, C.M., 3 letters
    - Maver, Mary, 3 letters
    - Mayer, Clara W., 2 letters
    - Mayer, Jean, 2 letters
    - Mayr, Ernst, 2 letters
    - Mazia, Daniel, 1952-1973; 11 letters
      Includes promotion recommendation for.
  - McC-Metr (Box 9)
    - McCann, Michael, 4 letters
    - McCarthy, Earl, 2 letters
    - McCarthy, Miles D., 1 letter
    - McCarty, Maclyn, 4 letters
    - McElroy, W.D., 4 letters
      Includes Stich recommendation.
    - McEwen, Bruce S., 1963-1974; 29 letters
      Includes recommendations for.
    - McGraw-Hill Book Co., 13 letters
      Includes comments on Katz "Nerve, Muscle and Synapse" and Prescott and Goldstein outline of "A Textbook of Cell Biology" (temporary title).
    - McGurrin, James, 1 letter
    - McIntyre, Peter. Peter Walker recommendation, 2 letters
    - McMaster, Philip M., 1 letter
    - McNamara, Peter, 2 letters
    - McWilliams, Jerry. College admission recommendations for, 4 letters
    - Meagher, W., 3 letters
    - Medical Library Center, 3 letters
    - Mednick, Sarnoff, 1 letter
    - Meinardi, H., 3 letters
    - Melchers, G., 3 letters
    - Melnick, Joseph, 1 letter
    - Menzel, Emil W., 1 letter
    - Merck, Sharp and Dohme, 1 letter
    - Mericle, L.W., 2 letters
    - Merrifield, Bruce. Recommendation to John Cushing, 2 letters
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1 letter
    - Mets, Laurens, 2 letters
    - Metz, Charles W., 2 letters
    - Meudt, Rudolph, 5 letters
      Includes medical school admission recommendation.
    - Middleton, Samuel, 3 letters
    - Miescher, Friedrich, 8 letters
      Includes correspondence with Karl Miescher; W.J. Whelan; Miescher portrait.
    - Miles Laboratories, 1 letter
    - Miller, David, 3 letters
    - Miller, Leon, 5 letters
    - Miller, Wm., 1 letter
    - Mills, G.T., 2 letters
    - Minagawa, Teiichi, 21 letters
    - Mirsky, I. Arthur; 1 item concerning Pauling boy, 1944-1970; 10 letters
    - Mirsky, Robert, 4 letters
    - Mishkin, Ricky, 2 letters
    - Mishra, N.K., 2 letters
    - Mishra, R.K., 2 letters
    - Missouri University of, 1 letter
    - Mitra, Sandhya, 3 letters
    - Mitsui, H., 2 letters
    - Mizuno, S., 2 letters
    - Moe, Harald, 2 letters
    - Mondal, Hrishikes, 2 letters
    - Monesi, Valerio. Concerning Marco Crippa, 2 letters
    - Monif, Gilles R.G. Recommendations for, 7 letters
    - Monr
    - Monroy, Alberto, 1950-1970; 91 letters
      Includes 1964 Apr Palermo lectures.
  - Mont-My (Box 10)
    - Montalenti, G., 1953-1964; 8 letters
      Includes 1964 Apr 29 Rome seminar.
    - Montana State College, 1 letter
    - Montefiore Hospital, 2 letters
    - Mookerjea, A., 1 letter
    - Moore, John A., 6 letters
    - Moore, John W. Bethesda seminar, 1954 February 4; 5 letters
    - Moore, Ruth, 1 letter
    - Moore, Stanford, 3 letters
    - Mora, Peter T. Items on 1964 May 1-3 Princeton Response weekend participant; Guggenheim fellowship evaluation; ms review submitted to PNAS, 15 letters
    - Morehouse, Ward, 5 letters
    - Mori-Chavez, Pablo, 3 letters
    - Morison, Robert F. Concerning A. Gallego, 2 letters
    - Morrill, Thomas, 2 letters
    - Morrison, James D., 2 letters
    - Morrison, John, 2 letters
    - Morton, Herbert, 1 letter
    - Moscona, A.E., 3 letters
    - Moses, Montrose, 3 letters
    - Mostny, Grete, 2 letters
    - Mothes, Kurt, 1 letter
    - Motz, Lloyd, 2 letters
    - Mudaliar, D.S. K. Radha thesis evaluation Mukherjee, A.B. (2), 6 letters
    - Muller, H.J., 7 letters
      Includes handwritten letter commenting on Darlington "The Facts of Life.
    - Müller, Paul, 1 letter
    - Munzer, Martha E., 3 letters
    - Murray, Ken, 3 letters
    - Muskie, Edward. Chairman, Select Senate Committee on Technology and Human Environment, 2 letters
    - Myers, Jack. George Webster recommendation, 2 letters
  - Na, 53 letters (Box 10)
    - National Academy of Sciences, 53 letters